Today, I'm going to talk about the subject of my talk,
which is the study of virtual fashion and the exploration of science and technology.
As soon as you hear this, you'll know that there are two parts to it.
One is teaching, and the other is science and technology.
Today, I'm going to share three parts.
The first part is to introduce the courses related to virtual fashion,
especially the one I'm teaching.
The second part is about the problems I encountered during my teaching process
and how I solved them.
The third part is about how we apply virtual fashion to science and technology.
President Jia has already introduced it,
so I won't go into details.
I graduated from Beijing Fashion College,
and then went to an outdoor clothing company.
Then I went back to school,
and I gave the school's creative products
a brand name of Bift Collection.
Then I went back to school, and I gave the school's creative products
Then I went back to school,
and I started to work on projects such as the Winter Olympics,
the National Day, the 70th Anniversary Exhibition, and so on.
and started to work on projects such as the Winter Olympics, the National Day, the 70th Anniversary Exhibition, and so on.
My current focus is on functional clothing design.
This focus mainly focuses on sports,
disabled people, elderly people, and classmates.
I'm going to introduce our courses.
Currently, we are working on a series of courses related to virtual clothing,
and we have a number of courses.
What I've come across are digital clothing technology courses.
The first course was taught by Professor Ma Kai at our school.
It started in 2019.
Our school has been the first digital experiment class
established since 2019.
In this experiment class, there were 30 students in the first year.
20 students were in design.
10 students were in the field of clothing factories.
The classes they took were pretty much the same.
The 30 students in the lab
took an exam in the first year of high school.
They took questions about their major, English,
and some questions about intelligence monitoring.
They took questions about the tests they took.
Last year, in 2013,
we graduated from the first digital experiment class in 2019.
I took part in their graduation design and graduation thesis.
Let me introduce the most intimate course we took with Kolo.
It's called Digital Costume Textile Technology.
The picture on the bottom left is a picture
I took when I was teaching my students.
It's a scene from my class.
We're in the digital experiment class,
the art class,
the fashion design course,
and the graduate course.
There are 36 courses in total.
During the course,
we teach the theory and practice of these subjects.
The main thing is to teach the theory and practice of these subjects.
That's the most important.
The basic principles and concepts
provide knowledge of the current digital and virtual costumes
and some of the concepts that are closely related to them.
The next stage is the behavioural and physical changes of virtual models,
the simulation and production of the common costumes,
the texture of the fabric and the production of the fabrics,
the setting and rendering of the scenes,
and finally,
We use a comprehensive class assignment to submit the homework.
What you see on this page are some of the examples we used in the teaching process.
For example, in the first class, we will introduce a very simple shirt or pants.
In the first class, we will leave the homework to the students first,
and then look at the level of understanding of the students.
In fact, in the previous class, we used a relatively short class to introduce some of the applications of the virtual clothing software.
So most of the students have already been in contact with it.
In addition, some of the students who are more interested in this aspect may have already learned a part of it through some teaching videos on the Internet.
So we will use this application to teach the students.
In order to understand the level of understanding of the students,
to see their current level,
it is generally not very good.
Most of the things are not very good.
So the problem is that this comparison is in line with our level of understanding during class.
Of course, there are also a few other students who are self-learning.
It is also very useful.
The bottom right corner of this page is the virtual model.
how to adjust the model's posture in the 3D window
and how to change the model's joints and posture.
The white mold in the middle is an old person's body shape.
We used an OBJ file to teach students
how to change the model's body shape and the makeup on top.
This is from the perspective of virtual models.
As for the clothing,
the one in the back is a case of the revision and 2D revision
before the revision.
The one on the top left is the second one.
We used the Beifu.
I used some of the Beifu's original design cases
to bring out some...
This is from the tie.
This is the pattern from the tie.
We took out the pattern from the photo
and used Photoshop or PixPlant
to create the pattern,
the pattern, the magic pattern, the discovery pattern,
the metal pattern and so on.
We used our own case examples,
including the Beifu logo.
The pink scene is to teach students
how to download some props from other websites
for the scene,
or how to make some props yourself
and how to place the characters on it.
This one is a demonstration of the teaching process.
This is some adjustment to the lighting and direction.
In the first eight classes,
we taught the models, the fabric, the clothing, and so on.
After the teaching,
in the last class,
we will give you the theme of the class,
so that we can explain it to you.
Each year,
each semester,
the themes of each semester are different.
What you see now is the theme of the last semester,
which is the semester that just ended in 2023.
We listed six of them,
cyberpunk,
because this is a hot topic these years,
cyberpunk and artificial intelligence,
sustainable design,
and traditional clothing restoration and innovation.
These four topics have been
very popular for the past few years.
The festival was held at the end of the year,
because Christmas,
New Year,
and Spring Festival
are coming soon.
So we want to add some related to the present,
as well as rural revitalization.
This rural revitalization
is to match two points.
One is the project that Beifu and Di Shang Group
did at that time.
This project is to develop clothing
for farmers and shepherds.
On the other hand,
last year,
ACDA,
which is a well-known design competition,
has such a theme.
So we put this kind of project with the school,
or some competition themes,
will also lead to our classwork.
Maybe those who are more experienced
will take the lead in this competition.
Now,
what you see here
is the class that just ended,
that is, the class that just ended in 2023.
At that time,
this class was the fashion engineering class.
That is to say,
the science students
did not design the students' backgrounds.
I found that one of the rules is that
the students in this class
are more inclined to choose traditional clothing,
or the theme of restoration or innovation.
Then,
if it is the students in the design class,
they will be more inclined to do other competitions,
or other options
to do some innovative design for the structure of the clothing.
These are the students
who did it relatively seriously.
The overall picture control is also good,
and the fashion simulation is also very good.
These are the traditional themes.
These are the students
who have a little bit of their own creativity.
After all,
they are engineering students.
Although this is a traditional concept,
they have done some innovative design designs.
This is a group of seconds.
It may be a group of seconds,
or a group of seconds.
A minority ethnic clothing.
They made some changes to the patterns.
This is some cyber
or animation themes.
The students' understanding of cyber
is the combination of machines and people.
This is a more popular game.
And the design of sports themes.
In addition to the class of digital clothing,
what you see now is the graduation of 2020,
which is our first digital experiment class.
This student happened to be
the graduation of me and another teacher last year.
I will show you the graduation video he made here.
You can hear the voice, right?
You can hear the voice.
I can hear you.
OK.
This student's design element is water.
This is the water.
So, in addition to the slope and the wave pattern of the water drop to the surface of the water,
he pulled it out and made it his fold.
In the end, he used the second set, which is the second set of white film on the screen, to make food.
In the end, he used the second set of white film on the screen, which is the second set of white film on the screen, to make food.
This is a video of him setting up.
This student is actually very solid in his work.
He is considered to be an excellent student among these students.
This student, in addition to the design of the water,
his thesis,
because our school,
his design and thesis are related to each other.
His thesis is about how to make folds in 3D software.
So he put himself,
we can take a look at this picture of his white film.
There are a lot of folds,
different types of folds.
So he put himself in this Clore.
Of course, he combined different software.
Blender, Clore,
he used several of them.
He used the method of making folds.
He wrote a paper on the method of making folds.
So this is another classmate who brought it last year.
This is the monitor of their class.
This classmate, he used this kind of ceramic pattern.
He made this pattern into clothing.
At first, there was one thing that became food.
Then, this one on the upper right corner.
This one on the upper right corner,
just made our last year's fashion week.
The cover of the class in Guangzhou.
The middle part was made into a 3D printing.
So this classmate's thesis is about 3D printing.
An analysis of the process of his practice.
Then the second part.
The second part is some of the problems I encountered in the teaching process.
First of all, the first question is that
different professional students
receive speed and creativity.
Because this software has one feature,
which is that it has a lot of tools.
It has a lot of 2D windows and 3D windows,
and so on.
So when you first get in touch with a classmate,
he often can't find the tools.
So for our course teaching group,
for this problem,
we used a lot of supporting tools.
For example, the Changjiang Yu Ke Tang.
This can only be entered into PPT or WPI.
Then we will record the process of demonstration and operation.
Then after class,
or when the classroom is in operation,
you can watch the playback.
You can watch the playback.
In this case,
because some students have seen the teacher demonstrate it once,
he will still encounter problems.
So we recorded such a video,
so he can watch it repeatedly.
The second method is that
based on my own experience,
I summarized some methods.
The second method is that based on my own experience,
Because the problem students encounter
is also encountered when I study these software.
And the age is older than the undergraduate students.
So the speed of contact may be slower than the students.
So I thought about it.
When I first got into this kind of software,
I would familiarize myself with several tools
when I operated a case.
I would write down the process,
and then take a screenshot of several key processes,
and put it in the instruction manual.
We will send the instruction manual to the students before class.
There is another benefit to this instruction manual.
For example, after the first class,
we will operate a case step.
Some students may finish it in 10 minutes.
Some students may not finish it in an hour.
During this time, if the students finish it quickly,
they can follow the second part of the instruction manual
and explore the operation step in advance.
This is a more convenient way.
The one on the right is the material I prepare every time before class.
This type of file is the screenshot of each step of my operation.
The one on the right is the file generated during my operation.
According to this logic,
I can write the instruction manual clearly enough for the students.
The third part is the problem that students ask for help the most.
This is the problem that students encounter the most after the demonstration.
The first problem is a relatively white question.
Where is the window tool?
Where is the tool that the students can't find?
Or is there something hidden that they can't find?
Then there is the file transmission.
For example, how to import the DXF file?
How to import the OBJ file?
Then how to output the rendering video?
Or how to export the quick photo?
How to apply some of the materials and textures in the drawing library to the attribute editor?
These problems are the first problems that students encounter when they first encounter this type of software.
The second type of problem is that they are not familiar with paper and craftsmanship.
Because this class is mainly for the second and third graders,
there are also students in the third grade.
Sometimes you will find that the problem they encounter is not because they are not familiar with the software,
but because they don't know how to sew this board.
I myself was also doing double-layer suits or coats.
Sometimes the embroidery is bad or the backstitch is bad.
I have to reflect on myself for a long time because I am not so familiar with the board.
This is a problem that is not solid in terms of clothing and paper.
The third small point is 3D space conversion.
For example, when you are doing some multi-layer or some clothes that need to be knitted,
or when you are doing this kind of board that will twist and twist,
you will find that the students can't distinguish between the front and the back.
They can't even distinguish between the left and the right.
For example, you need to move one side to the other side.
Because the space relationship is not good, they will move it from the back.
This is the kind of problem.
I think if you use too much of this, the problem will be solved.
The fourth small point is the problem of threading, crackling, and folding.
When I was just learning this software, I often encountered threading and cracking.
In general, you may want to insert a pair of pants into a piece of JPL file,
and then sometimes you may increase it, but you accidentally open it.
Or something like that.
There are some problems that will cause conflicts.
This is also often encountered.
The fifth small point is that even if you emphasize it in class,
you are very likely to encounter problems in the future.
Students will still do this every time.
How do you emphasize that in the end, there will still be some students who will solve the problems you emphasize?
The third part is how we apply virtual clothing to research.
I just entered the early stages of Beifu.
What I came across was some functional clothing for disabled people.
What you see is some of the work from 2008 to the present.
This is from 2008, it was called the Kangjian Clothing Research Center.
Later, in 2018, in the case of its predecessor, we adjusted it to the Wuzhai Clothing Research Center.
Until now.
Reunification again.
Now it's called.
Beautiful Life Clothing Research Center.
And then what you see is one of the people we focus on.
Later, before Beijing East Olympic Games,
18 to 19 years ago,
I received such a task from the Ministry of Science and Technology.
And then I did some for the athletes of the National Team of the Winter Olympic Games.
I applied some of the clothing for their special sports attitude.
In fact, we can see in the lower right corner,
some of the training clothes made for the Winter Olympic team.
We used these virtual software.
And then there are some other subsequent research projects.
It is mainly applied to, for example, the clothing of the elderly.
We went to get some body data and models of the elderly.
And then I took it to the Kolo.
To do it.
Of course, this is in progress.
To do some clothing-related research.
And then this is when teaching and science combined.
Some of the content made by students.
Just go on the platform.
Go to the platform to build.
According to the characteristics of the elderly.
And then I did some experiments with white paper.
This is currently in progress.
Digital experiment class graduation design.
It is based on that.
Some of the designs made by the group of people in Zhewan.
It is still in progress.
And the pants we made for the wheelchair developers in the previous period.
That's all for my sharing today.